<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grace Shopper on Beth Qiang</title>
    <link>http://bethqiang.com/tags/grace-shopper/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grace Shopper on Beth Qiang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://bethqiang.com/tags/grace-shopper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of Codsworth Robotics, the Beginning of Stackathon, and a Design Lecture</title>
      <link>http://bethqiang.com/post/codsworth-robotics-stackathon-design-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bethqiang.com/post/codsworth-robotics-stackathon-design-lecture/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We presented &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/post/what-ive-been-up-to-for-4-weeks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Codsworth Robotics&lt;/a&gt;, your one and only source for robot butlers, today in class. It&amp;rsquo;s officially live &lt;a href=&#34;http://codsworth-robotics.herokuapp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and you can view the code &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Codsworth-Robotics/codsworth-robotics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Although it still may be far from a production-ready app, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a fully-functioning e-commerce store, which is pretty impressive, if I do say so myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest moments of my young programming career so far happened on Monday night, when I hooked up the npm package &lt;code&gt;nodemailer&lt;/code&gt; to our checkout process, so that when a user places an order, they&amp;rsquo;ll immediately be sent an email with their confirmation number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/images/posts/2017-01/alfred-pennyworth.png&#34; class=&#34;center-img&#34; alt=&#34;Email from Alfred Pennyworth&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My teammates made fun of me a little bit for being so excited about this, and I can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; articulate why I was, except for that it was just a moment for me when I realized &lt;em&gt;how incredible programming can be&lt;/em&gt;. Which I realize still sounds a little weird, because, at its core, I just sent myself an email. But, a lot of seemingly disparate things came together at that moment for me, I think. (And let&amp;rsquo;s be real, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t want an email from Alfred Pennyworth?!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stackathon&#34;&gt;Stackathon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end of one project means the beginning of another! Today was the first day of Stackathon, which essentially is a personal hackathon. We have until Monday to build something (anything) of our choosing, and there are a couple of awards on the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After internally debating for basically the past month about what I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do, I finally decided to attempt an &lt;a href=&#34;https://altvr.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AltSpace&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://vtime.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;vTime&lt;/a&gt;-like app, but one that could support many more people than those currently do. As Mark Davis, Fullstack&amp;rsquo;s Product Manager, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fullstackacademy.com/blog/vr-lab-jan-2017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;describes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what we wish existed, now: a simple VR environment where up to 25 avatars can interact with each other, with real-time voice chat, that&amp;rsquo;s accessible on a Google Daydream headset as an MVP, but is also extensible to any WebVR enabled headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I only have five days, my primary goals will be to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Render a scene (I&amp;rsquo;m not worried about this part)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate with Firebase to support a lot of people joining (I&amp;rsquo;m more worried about this part), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use WebRTC for real-time audio communication (I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure this part is going to happen, but hey, reach for the stars?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d also love to pitch this to my Capstone Project team after, and build on top of it to create something even more amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve avoided seriously entertaining this idea pretty much since I started thinking about what I wanted to do, because every time I did, I would get overwhelmed and terrified. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited and intrigued by the VR space, but also terrified because of the sheer complexity of designing 3D environments and interactions with those environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite sayings is, &amp;ldquo;If your dreams don&amp;rsquo;t scare you, they&amp;rsquo;re not big enough.&amp;rdquo; I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s pretty applicable now — wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cto-lecture-design&#34;&gt;CTO Lecture: Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Senior Phase, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be having CTO Lectures on a regular basis. These are a series of lectures to expose us to the non-technical parts of building software, including design, scalability, agile, the &amp;ldquo;lean startup&amp;rdquo; methodology, etc. This was one of the parts about the program that I was looking forward to most, and today definitely did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We heard from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/oddurs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Oddur Sigurdsson&lt;/a&gt;, who previously was Creative Director at Fullstack. He worked in the software/design industry for a number of years, and now runs his own company. To become a designer, he argued, there are three steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play. You should be making something. Experiment. Share it with others. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ignore the rules.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan. Set guidelines for yourself. Set a direction (e.g., I want to be there in seven weeks, or two hours). Set goals, and don&amp;rsquo;t stop until you&amp;rsquo;ve achieved them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polish. Iterate and refine. Find the balance between functional and beautiful. Push the limits of your abilities. Get critical feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another one of his points was that there are striking similarities between programming and design, and I&amp;rsquo;d argue that these are very applicable to life as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking generally about being a designer and the process of design, Oddur pulled out Photoshop and Sketch and demonstrated his workflows and tools for editing photos and creating site/app designs. He spent maybe 20 minutes maximum designing in Sketch, but his design was absolutely gorgeous and I was blown away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I have an extra minute or two (so&amp;hellip;after Fullstack is over?), it&amp;rsquo;s definitely something I would love to delve into further. So much I want to do, so little time. Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shopping Carts &amp; Being Seniors</title>
      <link>http://bethqiang.com/post/shopping-carts-and-being-seniors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bethqiang.com/post/shopping-carts-and-being-seniors/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In the past few days, we&amp;rsquo;ve moved on from working primarily on the back-end of &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/post/what-ive-been-up-to-for-4-weeks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Codsworth Robotics&lt;/a&gt; to actually rendering the data our back-end is feeding to us. We&amp;rsquo;ve also started putting together an overall theme and look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The features I&amp;rsquo;ve primarily been working on have been the Orders History page for a logged in user, and I just started working on our cart. Relatively early on in the process, we decided we were just going to have our cart saved on the session, and never actually persisted in the database. One of the main challenges I&amp;rsquo;ve faced while doing this was coming to terms with the fact that we weren&amp;rsquo;t actually going to the database in our back-end route to fetch and update and delete items in our cart; we were just setting an array on the &lt;code&gt;req.session&lt;/code&gt; object. Though the premise was the same — the front-end would dispatch an action, that would send an AJAX request to our back-end, which would manipulate that array, then send the resulting array back to the front-end — it just felt a little strange doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary benefits, I think, to doing it this way are it&amp;rsquo;s a little less intensive on our server and it&amp;rsquo;s a little easier to transition someone&amp;rsquo;s cart when they&amp;rsquo;re not signed up or logged in originally to when they do sign up or log in. The drawbacks are, that let&amp;rsquo;s say someone&amp;rsquo;s kid throws some Pokemon&amp;rsquo;s cards into dad&amp;rsquo;s cart, and then dad actually signs in, dad probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t want those Pokemon cards. Likewise, if you put items in your cart when logged into a computer that&amp;rsquo;s not primarily yours, your cart will persist to the next person who uses that computer but when you log in via a different computer, your cart may* not be there anymore. And, this didn&amp;rsquo;t even occur to me until our fellow mentioned it, but we actually have no knowledge about what&amp;rsquo;s in our users&amp;rsquo; carts, so we can&amp;rsquo;t gather data about it or market to them or send them endless emails about things sitting in their carts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*We may be attempting to solve this in the near future by setting the session ID to be the user&amp;rsquo;s email. May, being the key word&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deployment-continuous-integration&#34;&gt;Deployment &amp;amp; Continuous Integration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also went through a workshop about how to deploy and run continuous integration our apps via &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.heroku.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://codeship.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Codeship&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve deployed apps to Heroku before, so I was relatively familiar with that process. But, I&amp;rsquo;ve never used any continuous integration tool before. Our first attempt at using CodeShip didn&amp;rsquo;t end up going so well — we ran into some errors, did something to fix it, ran into more errors, fixed those, then came across &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; errors&amp;hellip;until finally our fellow told us we were spending too much time on it and it might be a good idea to kind of sort of make our app somewhat functional before really worrying about it. So, we deleted that and moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did think the integration with CodeShip and Heroku was really cool; we could automate things to the point where all we&amp;rsquo;d have to do is push to GitHub, and then CodeShip would run, and then it would deploy automatically to Heroku. I&amp;rsquo;m excited for when we do get it to work to see all of it in action!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;not-project-related-things&#34;&gt;Not-Project-Related Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met with Career Services for the first time on Friday! Like most things in life, it was both wonderful and terrifying — wonderful because the future is always an exciting thing. Terrifying because, well, no one &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; likes the job hunt, do they?! We talked mostly about what I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, where I&amp;rsquo;m looking for it, and in general things I should be thinking about. I took some time over the weekend to research some companies to put on my &amp;ldquo;Companies I&amp;rsquo;d Love to Work For&amp;rdquo; list, which I&amp;rsquo;ll be building out over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also had our first Fullstack social with the new Remote cohort. First of all, it was a little weird (not in a bad way, just different&amp;hellip;) to see people who were not in our cohort in our video classroom! It was cool getting to meet and talk to the new class though, and we played some games together — &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/post/redux-authentication-and-social-activities/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Agamari&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://pathparadox.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Path Paradox&lt;/a&gt; (which was &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; built by a Fullstack group for their Capstone Project), and then I fought some zombies in Fullstack&amp;rsquo;s Minecraft world before calling it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve volunteered to be on the Senior Panel for this class this week — &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/post/node-shell-expressjs-and-senior-panel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;remember when my cohort was the one listening to the Senior Panel&lt;/a&gt;?! It&amp;rsquo;s crazy to think about. It&amp;rsquo;s also a little weird thinking about the fact that people are actually looking to us for guidance now, because I still often feel like I have no idea what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. (I&amp;rsquo;m told that this never really changes.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I&#39;ve Been Up To For The Past 4 Weeks</title>
      <link>http://bethqiang.com/post/what-ive-been-up-to-for-4-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bethqiang.com/post/what-ive-been-up-to-for-4-weeks/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m alive, I promise. Mostly. I&amp;rsquo;m just running on very little sleep. Also, can we talk about the fact that this is the first post I get to tag with &amp;ldquo;senior phase&amp;rdquo;?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about everything I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing since the last time I wrote about something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t me accidentally deleting my master branch of my blog. Over winter break, I:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-did, in its entirety, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bethqiang/game-of-life&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Game of Life&lt;/a&gt; using React and Redux. (&lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/post/game-of-life-with-react-and-redux/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; the post I wrote about the first half of it.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bethqiang/vr-winter-wonderland&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a baby WebVR + three.js app&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a snow scene with falling snow, like five trees, and a stationary penguin that I attempted to animate but would do weird things when I did. Weird penguin aside, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty rad. Also a cool and slightly surreal experience to view it in VR!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watched Guardians of the Galaxy for the first time and it was absolutely amazing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Re-did our &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bethqiang/authentication-data-flow&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Junior Phase workshop on authentication &amp;amp; OAuth&lt;/a&gt;. I felt like I definitely didn&amp;rsquo;t understand a lot of it the first time around, and going back a second time at least made me feel slightly better about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implemented most of &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bethqiang/todo-react-redux-immutable&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;a todo app&lt;/a&gt; using React, Redux, and Immutable.js. I used this to also practice some frontend testing. It was thrilling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started and finished most of my tech talk on Immutable Data &amp;amp; Immutable.js.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in the past four days, a lot has happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;grace-shopper&#34;&gt;Grace Shopper&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probably the biggest thing that&amp;rsquo;s happened is that we started our Grace Shopper project, an (eventually) fully-functioning e-Commerce store. Our store, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Codsworth-Robotics/codsworth-robotics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Codsworth Robotics&lt;/a&gt;, sells bots to help you with your gardening and cooking and butlering and general life-ing needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve personally worked on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting up ESLint and configuring it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a few of the database models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing tests for said models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding signup and login features and functions that filter based on authorization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And most recently writing the routes and views for users to view their orders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also just spent the last three hours trying and failing to fix a rather small but important thing (rendering the orders view automatically instead of on a click of a button, as it is right now), so this project is currently not on my list of favorite things ever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely been challenging trying to figure out what goes where and how all of the pieces fit together. It&amp;rsquo;s our first time creating a fully-fledged app with only a set of requirements and literally &lt;em&gt;nothing&lt;/em&gt; else. I 110% believe we&amp;rsquo;re definitely all capable of doing all of it and doing it well, but we&amp;rsquo;re still in some ways getting our bearings straight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also been an interesting experience working as part of a team on a longer-term and larger-scale project (instead of just having a pairing partner for a workshop and then getting a different partner the next day). We have three people in our group, and we&amp;rsquo;ve paired all together on some things, and we&amp;rsquo;ve worked completely independently of each other on others, and sometimes one person branches off on their own while the other two pair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of who works on what, everyone reviews all pull requests before we agree to merge, and it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not uncommon, if/when we&amp;rsquo;re working individually, for someone to pipe up and say, &amp;ldquo;Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m having trouble with this, can I share my screen and get y&amp;rsquo;all&amp;rsquo;s input?&amp;rdquo; Needless to say, I&amp;rsquo;ve also learned more of and become much more comfortable with Git over the past few days! I&amp;rsquo;m still very afraid of merge conflicts and Git yelling at me, but I&amp;rsquo;m sure I&amp;rsquo;ll get used to it eventually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tech-talk-immutable-data-immutable-js&#34;&gt;Tech Talk: Immutable Data &amp;amp; Immutable.js&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finished my tech talk. I really wanted to incorporate live coding instead of the code snippets at the end, but I was pushing the time limit before I put in the code at all. Next time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also presented it today. The good: I didn&amp;rsquo;t say &amp;ldquo;um&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;quite&lt;/em&gt; as much as I typically do when speaking in public. The bad: when I was re-watching myself, I noticed at least two mistakes in my slides, and I think I relied on my notes a little too heavily. But hey, only way to get good at something is to keep doing it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in seeing it, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IDf-tpuj8Kw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s already up on Fullstack&amp;rsquo;s YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;! The slides can be viewed &lt;a href=&#34;https://speakerdeck.com/bethqiang/immutable-data-and-immutable-dot-js&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stackathon&#34;&gt;Stackathon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another project that all Fullstack seniors do is the Stackathon project. We&amp;rsquo;re given four days to do literally anything we want, and we&amp;rsquo;re encouraged to work alone. (Although if you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want to work with another person, no one&amp;rsquo;s going to stop you.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My instructor and I have thrown around some ideas for what I could do. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards either creating a library that I can publish to npm, or an Electron app. (My idea right now for the latter basically amounts to a WYSIWYG editor to write in with an option to convert it to Markdown for static site generators.) I&amp;rsquo;m torn between these because I think writing my own legitimate library would be fun, but I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t get to do any front-end design, which really frustrates me sometimes but it&amp;rsquo;s also something I really enjoy. I keep hearing from people I trust that Electron isn&amp;rsquo;t terribly hard to learn, so I&amp;rsquo;ll probably take a look at it this weekend and see if it would be do-able to do what I want to do in the span of the four days we&amp;rsquo;ll be given.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m simultaneously really looking forward to working on this, but also somewhat scared as well. It&amp;rsquo;ll be something I choose and something that excites me, but if given the chance and an excuse, I work &lt;em&gt;way&lt;/em&gt; too much – and that&amp;rsquo;s not in the humble brag &amp;ldquo;I work too hard&amp;rdquo; kinda way. That&amp;rsquo;s an I&amp;rsquo;ll-stay-up-unhealthily-late-(until 5 am late, hello Tuesday night)-working-on-things-because-I-can-and-because-it&amp;rsquo;s-more-fun-than-sleep-and-because-things-not-being-perfect-bother-me kinda way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>