<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cto Lectures on Beth Qiang</title>
    <link>http://bethqiang.com/tags/cto-lectures/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cto Lectures on Beth Qiang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://bethqiang.com/tags/cto-lectures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The End of Codsworth Robotics, the Beginning of Stackathon, and a Design Lecture</title>
      <link>http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/01/18/codsworth-robotics-stackathon-design-lecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/01/18/codsworth-robotics-stackathon-design-lecture/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We presented &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/01/12/what-ive-been-up-to-for-4-weeks/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Codsworth Robotics&lt;/a&gt;, your one and only source for robot butlers, today in class. It&amp;rsquo;s officially live &lt;a href=&#34;http://codsworth-robotics.herokuapp.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, and you can view the code &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Codsworth-Robotics/codsworth-robotics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Although it still may be far from a production-ready app, it&amp;rsquo;s basically a fully-functioning e-commerce store, which is pretty impressive, if I do say so myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest moments of my young programming career so far happened on Monday night, when I hooked up the npm package &lt;code&gt;nodemailer&lt;/code&gt; to our checkout process, so that when a user places an order, they&amp;rsquo;ll immediately be sent an email with their confirmation number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/img/posts/2017-01/alfred-pennyworth.png&#34; alt=&#34;Email from Alfred Pennyworth&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My teammates made fun of me a little bit for being so excited about this, and I can&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; articulate why I was, except for that it was just a moment for me when I realized &lt;em&gt;how incredible programming can be&lt;/em&gt;. Which I realize still sounds a little weird, because, at its core, I just sent myself an email. But, a lot of seemingly disparate things came together at that moment for me, I think. (And let&amp;rsquo;s be real, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t want an email from Alfred Pennyworth?!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;stackathon&#34;&gt;Stackathon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end of one project means the beginning of another! Today was the first day of Stackathon, which essentially is a personal hackathon. We have until Monday to build something (anything) of our choosing, and there are a couple of awards on the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After internally debating for basically the past month about what I&amp;rsquo;ve wanted to do, I finally decided to attempt an &lt;a href=&#34;https://altvr.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AltSpace&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://vtime.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;vTime&lt;/a&gt;-like app, but one that could support many more people than those currently do. As Mark Davis, Fullstack&amp;rsquo;s Product Manager, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fullstackacademy.com/blog/vr-lab-jan-2017&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;describes&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what we wish existed, now: a simple VR environment where up to 25 avatars can interact with each other, with real-time voice chat, that&amp;rsquo;s accessible on a Google Daydream headset as an MVP, but is also extensible to any WebVR enabled headset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I only have five days, my primary goals will be to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Render a scene (I&amp;rsquo;m not worried about this part)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate with Firebase to support a lot of people joining (I&amp;rsquo;m more worried about this part), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use WebRTC for real-time audio communication (I&amp;rsquo;m not even sure this part is going to happen, but hey, reach for the stars?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d also love to pitch this to my Capstone Project team after, and build on top of it to create something even more amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve avoided seriously entertaining this idea pretty much since I started thinking about what I wanted to do, because every time I did, I would get overwhelmed and terrified. I&amp;rsquo;m very excited and intrigued by the VR space, but also terrified because of the sheer complexity of designing 3D environments and interactions with those environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite sayings is, &amp;ldquo;If your dreams don&amp;rsquo;t scare you, they&amp;rsquo;re not big enough.&amp;rdquo; I suppose that&amp;rsquo;s pretty applicable now — wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cto-lecture-design&#34;&gt;CTO Lecture: Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During Senior Phase, we&amp;rsquo;re going to be having CTO Lectures on a regular basis. These are a series of lectures to expose us to the non-technical parts of building software, including design, scalability, agile, the &amp;ldquo;lean startup&amp;rdquo; methodology, etc. This was one of the parts about the program that I was looking forward to most, and today definitely did not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We heard from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/oddurs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Oddur Sigurdsson&lt;/a&gt;, who previously was Creative Director at Fullstack. He worked in the software/design industry for a number of years, and now runs his own company. To become a designer, he argued, there are three steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Play. You should be making something. Experiment. Share it with others. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ignore the rules.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plan. Set guidelines for yourself. Set a direction (e.g., I want to be there in seven weeks, or two hours). Set goals, and don&amp;rsquo;t stop until you&amp;rsquo;ve achieved them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Polish. Iterate and refine. Find the balance between functional and beautiful. Push the limits of your abilities. Get critical feedback.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another one of his points was that there are striking similarities between programming and design, and I&amp;rsquo;d argue that these are very applicable to life as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After talking generally about being a designer and the process of design, Oddur pulled out Photoshop and Sketch and demonstrated his workflows and tools for editing photos and creating site/app designs. He spent maybe 20 minutes maximum designing in Sketch, but his design was absolutely gorgeous and I was blown away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I have an extra minute or two (so&amp;hellip;after Fullstack is over?), it&amp;rsquo;s definitely something I would love to delve into further. So much I want to do, so little time. Sigh.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>