<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Working Women Advocates on Beth Qiang</title>
    <link>http://bethqiang.com/tags/working-women-advocates/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Working Women Advocates on Beth Qiang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://bethqiang.com/tags/working-women-advocates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Working Women Advocates: HTTPS and the 50 Million Ways to Style React Components</title>
      <link>http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/03/23/working-women-advocates-https-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/03/23/working-women-advocates-https-css/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/02/23/every-new-beginning-comes-from-some-other-beginnings-end/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken on the roles of both CTO and a developer&lt;/a&gt; for an organization called &lt;a href=&#34;http://workingwomenadvocates.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Working Women Advocates&lt;/a&gt;. One of my classmates from Fullstack began the project while we were in the program, and we&amp;rsquo;re now working towards making it an official non-profit organization. Our mission is to create a safe and secure place for women to find and connect with advocates and allies to help them through the challenges of being a woman in the workplace, whether they’re actively facing hardships like discrimination or harassment, or they just need a friendly and sympathetic/empathetic ear to vent to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve brought on a project manager, have implemented an agile workflow, and have finally started setting deadlines for ourselves for the development process, so things have been moving along!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;setting-up-tls-ssl-https-for-a-custom-domain&#34;&gt;Setting Up TLS/SSL/HTTPS for a Custom Domain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things we wanted to do was obtain a TLS/SSL certificate and serve our entire site over HTTPS via our custom domain name. Up to this point, we had a basic static landing page hosted at our custom domain name, and our actual app was hosted on Heroku with a Heroku domain. As you can imagine, this was inconvenient to maintain and to move forward in the development process with. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t change anything on the front-end of our Heroku app because it was going to be overridden anyway by our current landing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of research into the different ways of going about this; from getting a certificate from &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LetsEncrypt&lt;/a&gt; and attempting to install it ourselves to using Heroku&amp;rsquo;s (at the time) beta SSL service to using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cloudflare.com/ssl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s free SSL service&lt;/a&gt;. We eventually decided to go with Cloudflare with our app hosted on Heroku because it was free, easy to set up and use, and widely used and trusted, despite &lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2017/02/23/major-cloudflare-bug-leaked-sensitive-data-from-customers-websites/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;recent news&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting this up was much easier than the research suggested. It essentially consisted of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a Cloudflare account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pulling our domain records from our domain provider (which Cloudflare simplified by pulling everything automatically)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Connecting our Heroku app to our custom domain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding a CNAME record in Cloudflare to point to our Heroku app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Somewhere in there, we also added a Cloudflare rule that said to always use HTTPS and redirect from HTTP if necessary.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;and voila, not even a few hours later, our Heroku app was accessible via our custom domain name and we were encrypted!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;styling-in-react-land&#34;&gt;Styling in React-land&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our MVP was built using React, &lt;a href=&#34;https://getmdl.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Material Design Lite components&lt;/a&gt;, and vanilla CSS. Our landing page was a static site built using Bootstrap and jQuery. Somehow, we had to get our static landing page into our MVP so that our &amp;ldquo;Join Us&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Donate&amp;rdquo; buttons were available, in addition to all of the quality information that Rachel had put on the landing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our temporary solution: put Bootstrap and jQuery into our MVP, stick the landing page in one giant component, and let that be that for a little while. Once we had that in place, we had to decide on how we wanted to proceed in the future in terms of our styling, and what we wanted to do about the slightly bloated mess that our codebase turned into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, styling in React-land is no simple task. There are approximately 50 million ways to do it: vanilla CSS, &lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://getbem.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;BEM&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://acss.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;atomic&lt;/a&gt;, inline, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/css-modules/css-modules&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;CSS modules&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.styled-components.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;styled components&lt;/a&gt;, the list goes on. Unfortunately, Bootstrap and jQuery don&amp;rsquo;t seem to be great options with React; because they operate on the real DOM, and React has its virtual DOM, those two can get out of sync and that can get sticky in some situations. I&amp;rsquo;ve read about &lt;a href=&#34;http://tech.oyster.com/using-react-and-jquery-together/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ways to use jQuery &lt;em&gt;inside&lt;/em&gt; of React components&lt;/a&gt;, and I think the idea is intriguing, but fancy animations and DOM interaction events can happen later. We needed to have some base to work off of before we can experiment with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/02/13/capstone-part-2-logging-in-the-chair-link-traversal/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used inline styles before&lt;/a&gt; and liked the modularity of it, but felt meh about the fact that it&amp;rsquo;s so limiting (e.g. no pseudoclasses and fun things like that, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/FormidableLabs/radium&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Radium&lt;/a&gt; only gets you so far). I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in CSS modules, but I also haven&amp;rsquo;t quite figured out how to use it successfully in conjunction with &lt;code&gt;react-bootstrap&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;material-ui&lt;/code&gt; yet. (I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s quite necessary for us, at least not yet, to create our own grid/components/etc. from scratch, so something that already exists would be nice.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re meeting about this to discuss how we want to proceed, so decision TBD! (Also mildly hilarious fact: I&amp;rsquo;m attending a meetup that&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;solely&lt;/em&gt; focused on styling in React in a few days, so it appears that I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one who&amp;rsquo;s confused and maybe slightly overwhelmed by all of this.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every New Beginning Comes from Some Other Beginning&#39;s End</title>
      <link>http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/02/23/every-new-beginning-comes-from-some-other-beginnings-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bethqiang.com/blog/2017/02/23/every-new-beginning-comes-from-some-other-beginnings-end/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well, folks. Fullstack&amp;rsquo;s officially over. (In fairness, it&amp;rsquo;s been over for almost a week now, and I just haven&amp;rsquo;t quite gotten around to writing about it.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s&amp;hellip;weird. You do this thing for 60+ hours a week for almost five months straight, and you see the same 15 other faces in little squares on your computer every day. And then you drink some wine and sit around with your classmates for a few hours and then on Monday you wake up and realize that you have all the time in the world. (And simultaneously somehow, no time at all.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was a little nervous about joining the first Remote Immersive cohort (it&amp;rsquo;s always scary being the first!), but having come out on the other side, I can most definitely say it is and will always be one of the best decisions I&amp;rsquo;ve ever made. I made lifelong friends and mentors, learned an incredible amount, and definitely grew as a developer, a teammate, and a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve waxed poetic and sentimental about my experience at Fullstack &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/tags/fullstack-reflections/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;many times before&lt;/a&gt;, so I&amp;rsquo;ll follow the principle of DRY and briefly just reiterate the quality of everything about the program. The curriculum was intense and challenging and sometimes made me want to cry, but it was also incredibly rewarding and enlightening. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have asked for a better group of people to have spent the past five months with, from my classmates and teammates who made working long hours a pleasure, to my instructors and fellows who constantly pushed us and encouraged us and weren&amp;rsquo;t afraid to admit that they sometimes didn&amp;rsquo;t know what they were doing either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout Senior Phase, we definitely had our ups and downs. In our &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/tags/fullstack-reflections/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Grace Shopper&lt;/a&gt; project, we learned how to work as a part of a team, how to use Git and GitHub without deleting our entire codebase (although we might have come close a few times), and how to create something substantial from end-to-end. During our final &lt;a href=&#34;http://bethqiang.com/tags/capstone-project/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Capstone project&lt;/a&gt;, we learned about WebRTC and race conditions (So. Many. Race conditions.) and using the entity-component-system and how to use a technology that&amp;rsquo;s on version 0.4.0 that none of us had touched before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the key lessons I&amp;rsquo;ll take away from Senior Phase and working collaboratively is that I don&amp;rsquo;t give enough positive feedback. When I gave code reviews, I had a habit of glossing over the positives, even though I thought them in my head, and focused instead on what I thought could be improved. When people spend hours grinding away at something and then are courageous enough to show the world (or at least, the other people working on the project), it can be a very vulnerable thing for them. Make those people feel welcomed, and valued, and point out the good things they did, &lt;em&gt;along with&lt;/em&gt; the things that you think could be improved. This is also vital to the mentoring work that I&amp;rsquo;m doing as well; coding is already somewhat frustrating endeavor, and it&amp;rsquo;s nice to know that you&amp;rsquo;re doing a thing or two right even when it seems like everything that can go wrong is going wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked hard, but we had some fun, too. One of my favorite memories was on a Friday afternoon, towards the end of Capstone, and all of us were overwhelmed and tired and maybe going a little crazy. We ended up having a team happy hour, where we grabbed our respective drinks and sort of did work but mostly talked about our lives and our hopes and our dreams and our view on politics and controversial issues. As a cohort, we also had a few spontaneous late-night conversations after the day was done, and I always enjoyed those thoroughly. We had game nights and Hot Seat and amazing (and sometimes embarrassing moments) caught and forever preserved on video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David and Nimit, Fullstack&amp;rsquo;s founders, by virtue of who they are and their efforts and the people that they&amp;rsquo;ve found to be on their team, have created something very special. Fullstack is one of the most inclusive, friendly, supportive, and fun environments I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been in, and in light of the tech industry&amp;rsquo;s ongoing issues with diversity and inclusiveness, that&amp;rsquo;s always an amazing thing to find and to be able to come back to. I&amp;rsquo;m sad to have my experience come to an end, but I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly grateful that I was able to become a part of the Fullstack community and that I&amp;rsquo;ll forever get to be a part of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-s-next&#34;&gt;So, what&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m officially on the job hunt! My primary focus will be in the Austin area, but I&amp;rsquo;m definitely not opposed to moving for the right opportunity. If you know anyone looking for junior devs, I&amp;rsquo;d love to chat! And if you don&amp;rsquo;t have or know someone who has jobs, but have advice that you want to offer, I&amp;rsquo;m all ears. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More importantly, I have a few fun things in the pipeline:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few personal projects — first up will probably be a rich-text-with-spell-check-to-markdown app that I was considering doing for my Fullstack hackathon project. More details TBD. I also really want to finally actually learn Elm and C#/Unity (I know, those are two very different things)&amp;hellip;but the whole 24-hours-in-a-day thing is inconvenient.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to get involved in an organization like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codeforamerica.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Code for America&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techforcampaigns.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tech for Campaigns&lt;/a&gt; or something where I can use my technical skills to enable civic engagement. I still need to do some research and see how I want to proceed with this, but it&amp;rsquo;s most definitely a prominent part of my agenda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing to be a part of Women Who Code, giving talks, and mentoring women who are just getting their feet into the coding waters. Come join me at a Women Who Code event around Austin! I&amp;rsquo;m also in the process of expanding my meetup scene a bit, so if you have suggestions, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to hear them! I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for anything in particular; mostly just an easy-going community who likes to geek out about code.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve signed on to help a classmate, &lt;a href=&#34;http://rachelbird.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rachel&lt;/a&gt;, with a project she started at Fullstack that she&amp;rsquo;s now turning into a legitimate non-profit. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://workingwomenadvocates.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Working Women Advocates&lt;/a&gt;. We hope it&amp;rsquo;ll serve as a place for women to find and connect with advocates and allies to help them through being a woman in the workplace, whether they&amp;rsquo;re actively facing challenges like discrimination or harassment, or they just need a woman&amp;rsquo;s ear to vent to. While doing research for this project, Rachel was suprised to find out that nothing like this really existed — so here we are! I&amp;rsquo;ll be focused primarily on the dev/tech side, and we have other people who are better than me at other things to do those other things, but we&amp;rsquo;re definitely still looking for more help. Come check us out, and let us know if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in offering your skills or a small donation! (We&amp;rsquo;re in the process of setting up a legitimate non-profit, but unfortunately we can&amp;rsquo;t offer tax-deductible donations at the time!) We&amp;rsquo;ve received a lot of positive feedback so far, as well as a lot of interest in helping us, and we&amp;rsquo;d love for you to be a part of it!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>